(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T22:37:50.529414",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
3周年ありがとう！これからもずっと君と一緒に！
Thank you for the 3rd anniversary! I want to be with you forever!
ホロライブに入る！！
I'm joining Hololive!!
あぁ いつものように 過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
Ah, as always, I yawn at the passing days.
さんざめく夜 越え 今日も
Passing through the noisy night, today again,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning descends upon the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような
Feeling somewhat empty,
そんな気持ち つまらないな
a feeling like that is so boring.
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ
But that's fine, that's just how it is.
これでいい
This is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた
Without realizing it, I kept hiding it.
本当の声を響かせてよ ほら
Let your true voice resonate, come on!
見ないフリしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこにある
it's definitely right there.
あぁ 感じたままに描く
Ah, drawing just as I feel,
自分を選んだその色で
with the colors I chose myself.
眠い空気纏う朝に
In the morning wrapped in sleepy air,
訪れた青い世界
a world of blue has arrived.
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying I like what I like
怖くて仕方ないけど
is frightening beyond help, but
本当の自分 出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I finally met my true self.
あぁ 手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに
Ah, the more I reach out my hands,
遠くへゆく
the further away it gets.
思うようにいかない今日も
Even today when things don't go as planned,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I'm frantically struggling once again.
悔しい気持ちも ただ情けなくて
Even this frustration feels pathetic,
涙が出る
bringing tears to my eyes.
踏み込むほど 苦しくなる
The further I step in, the harder it gets,
痛くもなる
and the more it hurts.
あぁ 感じたままに進む
Ah, moving forward just as I feel,
自分を選んだこの道を
down this path I chose for myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
On nights rubbing heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung to that blue vow.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what I love
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
isn't just about "fun."
本当にできる？ 不安になるけど
"Can I really do this?" I get anxious, but...
あぁ 何枚でも ほら何枚でも
Ah, no matter how many pages, see, no matter how many,
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
I drew them because I lacked confidence!
あぁ 何回でも ほら何回でも
Ah, no matter how many times, see, no matter how many times...
何回でも
No matter how many times,
積み上げてきたことが
what I've built up
武器になる
becomes my weapon.
周りを見たって
Even if I look around,
誰かと比べたって
or compare myself to others,
僕にしかできないことは何だ
what is it that only I can do?
今だって自信なんかない
Even now, I have no confidence,
それでも
but still...
感じたことない気持ち
Feelings I've never felt before,
知らずにいた思い
thoughts I never knew I had,
あの日踏み出して
stepping out that day,
初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
even all of this pain I felt for the first time,
好きなものと向き合うことで
by facing what I love,
触れたまだ小さな光
I touched a light, still small.
大丈夫
It's alright,
行こう
let's go,
あとは楽しむだけだ
now all that's left is to enjoy it!
Ah すべてを賭けて描く
Ah, risking everything to paint,
自分にしか出せない色で
with colors only I can create.
朝も夜も走り続け
Running through day and night,
見つけ出した青い光
I found that blue light.
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing what I love,
今だって怖いことだけど
even now it's scary,
もう今はあの日の透明な僕じゃない
but now, I'm no longer that transparent me from back then.
Ah ありのままのかけがえのない僕だ
Ah, I'm irreplaceable just as I am.
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hidden away,
本当の声を聞かせてよ
let your true voice ring out!
ほら 見ないフリしていても
Look, even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこに
it's definitely right there,
今もそこに
still right there even now.
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hidden away,
本当の声を聞かせてよ
let your true voice ring out!
さあ 見ないフリしていても
Come on, even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこに
it's definitely right there,
君の中に
inside of you.
ダメダメダメの脳味噌の中から やめろバカとわめくモラリティ
"No, no, no," my brain screams from deep inside, "Stop it, you idiot!", my morality cries out.
ダーリンベイビー ダーリン 半端なくラブときめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
Darling, baby, darling, with insane love and fluttering excitement, a philosophy on edge.
死ぬほど可愛い？ 上等かい？ 何がし法に触れるくらい
Deadly cute? Isn't that great? Enough to practically break the law.
ばら撒く乱痴気 気づけば当事 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Scattering frenzy, before I know it I'm lost in it, it's your fault for being born in this world.
やたらとしんどい 心患い バラバラな脳みそとこの身体
Excessively painful, a sickness of the heart, a fragmented brain and body.
けど脈打つアイラブユー 吹き出てアイリスアウト
Yet my pulsating "I love you" gushes out and iris out.
言いたい事何？ この思いをどうしよう
What do I want to say? What should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥のザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
Sugar crystals deep in my ribs melt, about to turn into vomit.
瞳孔バチライで溺れ死にそう
Pupils dilated, feeling like I'm drowning to death,
今この世で君だけ大正解
in this world right now, only you are the absolute answer.
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling, darling, darling...
ひっくり返っても勝ち目はない 君だけルールは適用外
Even if I flip belly-up, there's no chance of winning, only for you, the rules don't apply.
オセロの黒を四つ置かない 勝機挙げ阻害
Four black discs in Othello, blocking my chances of victory.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラで おでこにスティグマ 申し訳ないな
With the Avada Kedavra you shot at me with a smile, a stigma on my forehead, I'm so sorry.
いや射して 貫いて ここ弱点
No, pierce me, run me through, right here at my weak point.
死ぬほど可愛い？ 上等かい？ 何がし法に触れるくらい
Deadly cute? Isn't that great? Enough to practically break the law.
ばら撒く乱痴気 気づけば当事 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Scattering frenzy, before I know it I'm lost in it, it's your fault for being born in this world.
偽物でもいい 何でもいい 今君と紐付いてるすべて欲しい
Fake is fine, anything is fine, I want everything connected to you right now.
けど脈打つアイラブユー 吹き出て
Yet my pulsating "I love you" gushes out...
アイリスアウト
Iris out!
言いたい事何？ この思いをどうしよう
What do I want to say? What should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥のザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
Sugar crystals deep in my ribs melt, about to turn into vomit.
瞳孔バチライで溺れ死にそう
Pupils dilated, feeling like I'm drowning to death,
今この世で君だけ大正解
in this world right now, only you are the absolute answer.
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling, darling, darling...
しゅぴしゅわ〜！ 属性充填足りてる？
Shupishuwa~! Are your attributes fully charged?
ホロライブDEV_IS FLOWGLOWのイロアイ電波担当、水宮すうでーす！
I'm Mizumiya Suu from hololive DEV_IS FLOWGLOW, in charge of color electro-magnetic waves!
と言うことで『STEP INTO DREAMS』始まりましたー！
And so, "STEP INTO DREAMS" has begun!
今回はですね、オープニングにもあった通り
This time, as shown in the opening...
夢だった、ホロライブに入って夢だった、初めてのソロ生...
...my dream of joining hololive, and my dream of having my very first solo live performance...
ソロライブということで、イエーイ！
Since it's a solo live, yay!
ちょっとめちゃくちゃに緊張しているんですけれども、
I'm super nervous right now, but...
どうだった？ 群青のアイリスアウト、コメント欄どうだった？ かっこよかった？
How was it? "Gunjou no Iris Out", how was the chat? Was it cool?
「かっこよかった」ってきっと、まあこの後流れるんだろうな。かっこよかっただろ？
Comments saying "It was cool" will surely flow in later. I was cool, right?
いっぱい褒めてください！
Please give me lots of compliments!
今回はですね、タイトルにもある通り、
This time, as mentioned in the title,
もうステップがもう、はちゃめちゃにもステップが…ステップがはちゃめちゃに多かったりですね、
the dance steps... there are an insanely huge number of steps,
あとは、やったことのないジャンルのダンスにも挑戦しちゃったりしていますので、
and I'm also challenging dance genres I've never done before,
お楽しみに！
so please look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにあるハッシュタグ「#水宮すう生誕祭2026」です！
The hashtag is the one right here, "#MizumiyaSuuBirthday2026"!
スクショとか感想とかたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you posted lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せトレンド！
Aiming for trending!
みんな、いっぱいツイートしてね！
Everyone, tweet a lot, okay?
この後はですね、ゲストパートにもいきたいと思っているの…
Next up, I want to move on to the guest section...
ですが！
...however!
なんとお祝いの映像が届いてるみたいなので、見てみましょう！
It seems a congratulatory video message has arrived, so let's check it out!
こっちかな？
Is it over here?
よーし。
Alright.
なんだなんだ？
What is it, what is it?
キミを笑顔へご案内！ 欒風の観光大使でにじさんじ所属、綾柿の末広、しがりこだよ！
Guiding you to smiles! I'm Shigariko, the Ranfu tourism ambassador from Nijisanji, the last blossom of Ayagaki!
りこー！
Riko~!
水宮、お誕生日おめでとう！
Mizumiya, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you~!
きっと今、水宮は最高のライブをしていることでしょう！
I'm sure Mizumiya is putting on the best live performance right now!
本当におめでとう！
Truly, congratulations!
本当ね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、どうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで、お祝いのメッセージ動画を今回送らせていただいております。
Honestly, I really wanted to celebrate with you in person, but our schedules couldn't align, so I sent this video message instead.
水宮とはね、同期としてもうたくさんコラボして、プライベートとかでもテーマパーク行ったりとか、
As genmates, Mizumiya and I have collaborated a lot, and in private we've gone to theme parks together,
行ったー！
We did!
映画も行ったりとか、
gone to the movies,
近々でお泊まりするくらいの…
and even stayed over at each other's places...
ちょっと仲良くね、させてもらってて、本当にいつもありがとう！
We've been really good friends, so thank you so much, as always!
事務所がね、違うのにもこんなに仲良くなれるなんて、
Even though we're from different agencies, becoming this close...
もうめっちゃ嬉しいし、いつも水宮に元気もらって、支えてもらってます。
...makes me super happy, and I always get energy and support from Mizumiya.
これからもずっと友達でいてね！
Let's stay friends forever!
いっぱい遊んで、いっぱい楽しいことしていこうね！ 大好きだよ！
Let's hang out a lot and do lots of fun things! I love you!
それでは、しがりこでした！ この後もライブ楽しんでね！ 頑張れ！
Well then, this was Shigariko! Enjoy the rest of the live! Do your best!
ありがとうー！
Thank you~!
ということで、しがりこからメッセージが来ました！ ありがとう、しがりこー！
And with that, a message came from Shigariko! Thank you, Shigariko~!
こっちにいるかな？ ありがとう、しがりこー！
Are you over here? Thank you, Shigariko~!
いやーそう、今回はね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、
Yeah, so our schedules couldn't line up this time,
ちょっとリコの3Dにはね、ちょっと呼んでもらって一緒に踊ったんですけど、
I was invited to Riko's 3D live before and danced together,
ちょっとすうのライブでは今回は踊れなかったけど、
but unfortunately she couldn't dance at Suu's live this time.
いつか一緒にまた踊ろうね！
Let's dance together again someday!
ありがとうね、リコ！ 水宮頑張るよ！
Thank you, Riko! Mizumiya will do her best!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲に行こうかな？
Now that I've gotten her support, shall we move on to the next song?
ちょっと次はゲストパートだから、誰が来るのかな？
Next is the guest section, so I wonder who's coming?
このあともまだまだ続きます！
There's still much more to come!
そしてなんか告知もあるかもしれないので、
And there might even be some announcements,
最後まで楽しんでねー！
so please enjoy until the very end~!
昔々のそのまた昔 とある貴族の
Once upon a time, long long ago, in a noble family,
仲良しな兄弟
there were close-knit siblings...
（以下略称） 「ちゃんとやれ！」
(Abbreviated below) "Do it properly!"
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ ヨーイドン！
The butler calls, take your seats, ready set go!
ナイフとフォークで 応戦いたしますの
We shall fight back with knife and fork!
だっ僕らはブルジョアの 立派な立派な貴族様なんですの
After all, we are bourgeois, fine and splendid nobles!
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
Bow down, foolish commoners! I'll show you the viceroy difference between us!
おい待て待て まったくさーん
Hey, wait, wait! Honestly, man...
見逃すような ハッタリかまして
pulling a bluff that anyone could see through.
はいはいはいはい お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
Yes, yes, as my elder brother commands (lol)!
あーむかつくぜ！ マジむかつくぜ！
Ah, so annoying! Seriously annoying!
兄に対して 生意気な態度
That cheeky attitude toward your elder brother!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Battle cry! Sound the gong!
ケンカ勃発で 宣戦布告
Outbreak of a fight, a declaration of war!
いたずらして 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, getting carried away,
ほらほら煽ってく Style で
look, look, in our provocative style!
大安売り 買っちゃったら
A bargain sale! If you fall for it,
毎度ありがとで 君の負け！
thanks every time, and you lose!
引き出しと煽り合いの 駆け引きで決める
Deciding through tactics of tricks and taunts,
威厳見せるためあえてため 火花散る両者の目と目
pausing on purpose to show dignity, sparks flying between our eyes!
俺を誰だと思ってる 喰らえ！ 俺様がルールブック
Who do you think I am? Take this! I am the rulebook!
へたれじゃない！ 酔ってない！ ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ！
I'm no wimp! I'm not drunk! I just lack a little courage!
さあさあ皆さんお手を拝借 当たり前だろ優勝者取れ
Come on everyone, give us a clap! Naturally, claim the victory!
生まれながらにしてチート やべぇ閃く人生がスタート
Born a cheat, an awesome inspiring life begins!
当然です皆様 優勝はガチ勢！
Naturally, everyone, victory goes to the hardcores!
ハイ論破 ハイ論破 ハイ論破 貰ってくぜ勝哉！
Total defeat! Total defeat! Total defeat! Taking the victory!
はーい はい はい はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes
はなまる よくできました☆
Full marks! Well done! ☆
あーむかつくぜ！ まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, so annoying! Super annoying!
僕に向かって 減らず口なんぞ
Talking back to me like that,
とっておきを 君に見舞え
I'll show you my secret weapon!
報復 制裁 挑発しちゃって
Retaliation, sanction, provoking you!
いじわるして 一枚上
Being mean and staying one step ahead.
チャンスは 貰っていくスタンスで
Taking every chance I get,
痛恨ミス！ あっちゃっちゃぁ
A critical mistake! Oh dear!
おあいにくさまだね 君の負け
Too bad for you, you lose!
YES!
だけどキミ キミだけが
But you, only you,
僕に似合いのライバル
are my true rival.
落ちるのも 凹んでんのも
Falling down or feeling down,
調子狂わされるから
you throw me off my game,
今夜もてめぇと やいやいやいやい
so tonight again, I'll fight with you!
大体に兄様がいつもそうやって
Generally, elder brother is always...
ナヨナヨしてるから僕が兄様の分まで積極的になってやってやってんだよ
being so spineless, so I'm taking charge for you!
年上のくせに全然頼りにならないお兄様とか名ばかりだよもう
Even though you're older, you're so unreliable!
今日から僕が兄だ これ決定！
From today, I'm the older one! It's decided!
ハイ決定！
Yes, decided!
あーむかつくぜ！ まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, so annoying! Super annoying!
憎まれ口は お口をチャック
Zip your mouth if you're gonna talk smack!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Sound the war cry, ring the gong!
次世代エンペラーは この俺だ！
The next-generation emperor is ME!
悪戯して 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, getting carried away,
ほらほら 煽っていくStyleで
look, look, provoking in style!
1から100 いただきます
Taking it all from 1 to 100!
毎度ありがとうで 君のま...
Thanks as always, it's your...
まさかの 引き分け？！
Wait, a draw?!
えーっ
Ehh?!
この頃君が纏う「しつけ直し」の季節の匂い
Lately, the scent of the season of 're-disciplining' surrounds you.
したたかな佇まいの割に脆いソコに触れるの
Despite your cunning presence, I touch that fragile spot of yours.
あぁ 怒らないで darling だってホントのことだもん 体ばっかデカくなって 中身はガキだよね
Ah, don't get mad, darling! After all, it's just the truth. Your body grew up, but inside you're still a brat.
暴れないで doggie 私華奢な手だから リードなんて気まぐれで パッと落としちゃうかも
Don't thrash around, doggie. My hands are delicate, so I might carelessly drop your leash on a whim.
だらしなーい！ 意気地なーい！ ホント君は救えない！ 堕落に耽っちゃってご愁傷様
Sloppy! Spineless! Honestly, you're hopeless! My condolences for indulging in corruption.
夢がなーい！ 糧もなーい！ くせに愛は欲しいの？ なら3回回ってお手から...
No dreams! No goals! Yet you still want love? Then turn around 3 times and give me your paw...
妬み 嫉み 人の企み この世は罠だらけ ねぇ ずっとここにいて？
Envy, jealousy, human schemes—this world is full of traps. Hey, stay here forever, okay?
ひれ伏して doggie 生まれ持った才と脳で 全部を黙らせて 今日も稼いじゃう私の前に
Prostrate yourself, doggie. With my innate talent and brain, I hush everything and earn again today in front of me.
Follow or die でも餌は気分次第 ねぇ ワタシを知らなかった頃の日々に戻りたい？
Follow or die, but your treats depend on my mood. Hey, do you want to return to the days before you knew me?
Walk into a trap 無知な babe 侵す drug もうワタシを知らなかった頃のキミは戻らない
Walk into a trap, naive babe, a drug that infests. The you who didn't know me can never return.
だらしなーい 意気地なーい ホント君は救えない どこにも行けないね
Sloppy, spineless, honestly you're hopeless. You can't go anywhere, can you?
くだらなーい！ 果てしなーい！ こんな広い世界で 私に堕ちていく君が好き！
Pointless! Endless! In this vast world, I love watching you fall for me!
夢がなーい！ 糧もなーい！ くせに愛が欲しいの！ なら3回回ってお手から...
No dreams! No goals! Yet you want love! Then turn around 3 times and give me your paw...
お探しのページは現在使われておりません。
The page you are looking for is currently unavailable.
意味わかんねぇ！
Makes no sense!
どうせ誰も聴いてなんかないさ
At any rate, no one is listening anyway.
音楽なんて全部ファッション
Music is all just a fashion statement.
音楽家ぶって選手退場ワンナイ
Pretending to be musicians, exiting after one night.
どうせ何も伝えてなんかないさ
At any rate, nothing is being conveyed.
なんとかトック撮って売名 あんなどやっておいて最低グンナイ
Making TikToks to chase clout, acting so cocky, then "lowest good night."
どうしたってどう見たって尊師達でもう大渋滞
No matter how you look at it, gurus are jamming up the scene.
それにもあっちこっちそっちぼっち卍Zエイジ猿も欲しがる
Even so, Gen-Z apes over here, there, and everywhere want it too.
パンチライン欲しいの 意味とか どっちだっていいよ
Wanting a punchline; meaning or whatever, either is fine.
歌詞とかどうでもいいのでノれるの下さい
Lyrics don't matter, just give us something to groove to.
さぁみんなで笑いましょう
Come on, let's all laugh together.
芸術より数の大小？
Is quantity greater than art?
ヴァイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price paid to the virus.
じゃあどうすんの それでいいんだっけ？
So what do we do? Was that really okay?
頭は空回り 蝕んでいく
My mind is spinning in circles, rotting away.
ふざけるな
Don't screw with me!
バイバイ バズ メロディ 疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Bye-bye, viral melody. Doubt it, it's mostly lies.
化けんな 幻想 でも 理想 でもいい
Don't pretend; illusion or ideal, either is fine.
君の歌いたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでもオーライ 嘘じゃない
Even if clumsy, it's alright, it's not a lie.
お金や擬奏で満たす前に
Before filling yourself with money or fake playing,
負けんな 覚醒せよ 鼓動達よ
don't lose, awaken, beats of the heart!
君の伝えたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to convey?
意味わかんねぇ！
Makes no damn sense!
※お書きになったそんな音楽は現在使われておりません ポップソング、ヒットソング聴いてもう一度お書き直しください
[Announcement: The music you wrote is currently not in use. Please listen to pop songs and hit songs, and rewrite it again.]
あーもうハイカラ作家ばっか洒脱臭いわぁ
Ah, enough with these stylish writers acting all sophisticated...
どいつもしこいつもそいつがあいつが
Every single one of them, this guy, that guy,
意味わかんねぇ！
makes no damn sense!
どうしたってどう見たって尊師達でもう大渋滞
No matter how you look at it, gurus are jamming up the scene.
それにもあっちこっちそっちぼっち卍Zエイジ猿も欲しがる
Even so, Gen-Z apes over here, there, and everywhere want it too.
パンチライン欲しいの 意味とか どっちだっていいよ
Wanting a punchline; meaning or whatever, either is fine.
歌詞とかどうでもいいので伸びるの下さい
Lyrics don't matter, just give us something that goes viral.
さぁみんなで祓いましょう
Come on, let's exorcise it all together.
芸術より数なん・でしょう？
Numbers over art, right?
ヴァイラスに酷い代償
A terrible price paid to the virus.
じゃあどうすんの？ それでいいんだっけ？
So what do we do? Was that really okay?
頭は空回り 蝕んでいく
My mind is spinning in circles, rotting away.
ふざけるな
Don't screw with me!
バイバイ バズ メロディ 疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Bye-bye, viral melody. Doubt it, it's mostly lies.
化けんな 幻想 でも 理想 でもいい
Don't pretend; illusion or ideal, either is fine.
君の歌いたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底終われない
There's no way it can end like this.
欲しいのはきっとお金じゃない
What I want surely isn't money.
負けんな 覚醒せよ 鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, beats of the heart!
君の歌いたかった物がきっとあるんだ
There's surely something you wanted to sing.
ふざけるな ふざけるな！
Don't screw around, don't screw around!
バイバイ バズ メロディ 疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Bye-bye, viral melody. Doubt it, it's mostly lies.
化けんな 幻想 でも 理想 でもいい
Don't pretend; illusion or ideal, either is fine.
君の歌いたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでもオーライ 嘘じゃない
Even if clumsy, it's alright, it's not a lie.
お金や擬奏で満たす前に
Before filling yourself with money or fake playing,
負けんな 覚醒せよ 鼓動達よ
don't lose, awaken, beats of the heart!
僕の伝えたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing I wanted to convey?
意味わかんねぇ！
Makes no damn sense!
意味わかんねぇよ！
It makes no damn sense!
意味わかんねぇ！
Makes no damn sense!
せーの！ すーちゃん！ お誕生日おめでとう！
Ready, set... Suu-chan! Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
何歳になったわけ？
How old did you turn?
20歳バージョン2！
20 years old, version 2!
いいね！ バージョン2！ ありがとう！
Nice! Version 2! Thank you!
ちょっとみんな、せっかく来てくれ...
Hey everyone, since you all came...
あらあらあら...！ 大丈夫？
Oh dear, oh dear! Are you okay?
あんた違うでしょ！
You're not the one, are you?!
まあ今日の主役ですから、瑞々は！
Well, Mizumizu is today's star, after all!
ちょっとみんなに一言言っていってもらおうかなって。
So I thought I'd have everyone say a few words.
1人ずつ来なよ、ほら。普通にほら、愛をね...
Come up one by one, come on. Normally, you know, with love...
人が多くて行ききれない、ほら... 誰から？ほら...
There are too many people, I can't reach... Who's first? Come on...
いや、えーっと...ママだよ。
No, uh... I'm your mama.
おめでとう！ おめでとうじゃない！
Congratulations! Don't "congratulations" me!
おめでとう！ この動き！ なにそれ！
Congratulations! Look at these moves! What is that?!
もう、ほらちゃんとして！ 大丈夫？変な人いて怖かったでしょ？
Geez, come on, act proper! Are you okay? There was a weird person, scary, right?
なんかおかしくね？ ママだよ。
Isn't something weird? I'm your mama.
違うよ！違う！ ママなの！
No! You're wrong! I am your mama!
おかしい... おかしい...
This is weird... so weird...
ちょっと待って！ うちの事務所さ、なんかアレじゃないのよ。芸人じゃないのよ。
Wait a minute! Our agency isn't, like, that. We aren't comedians.
溜まってたからビビった。 おーおー。
They were holding it in, so I was startled. Oh, oh.
はい、これからも頼りになるお姉ちゃんに頼ってね！
Alright, rely on your dependable big sister from now on, okay?
お姉ちゃんだと思ってるの？本当に？
Do you really think you're a big sister?
おかしいよ！ おかしいよ！
That's weird! That's weird!
ほら、ちゃんとほら、愛をね。最後にね、フツーにね。
Come on, properly, show some love. At the end, normally.
いや、でもうちらーの「すーびび」の仲やんかー。 そうね！
Well, but we're in "SuuBibi" together, right? That's right!
だから「せーの」って言ったら...
So if I say "Ready, set...", what will...
分かったよな？
You got it, right?
分かった！
Got it!
行くよ！せーの！
Here we go! One, two...
スリー、ツー、ワン...
Three, two, one...
待って待って！
Wait, wait!
もう一回！
One more time!
せーの！スリー、ツー、ワン、サーイコー！
Ready, set! Three, two, one, awesome!
ハート！これハートだよ！
A heart! This is a heart!
大丈夫？届いてる？
Are you okay? Is it reaching?
しっかりして！
Pull it together!
ありがとう！みんなー！
Thank you, everyone!
ママ、ママ良かったよー！
Mama, Mama, you were great!
よかったよ！
You did great!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
対戦ありがとうございました！
Thanks for the great fight!
何かうるさかったなー
Man, that was kinda noisy...
頑張るか。よし！
Alright, let me do my best. Okay!
くだらない愛の結果で
As a result of foolish love,
僕らは生まれ落ちて
we were born into this world,
呼吸すら強いられているけれど
forced even to just breathe, and yet...
綺麗な言葉並べて
Lining up pretty words,
醜さに蓋をして
putting a lid on the ugliness,
自分を愛せないままだな
I still can't bring myself to love who I am.
波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること。
[Title: Nami ni Namae wo Tsukeru Koto, Bokura no Kokyuu ni Owari ga Aru Koto.]
くだらない嘘をつくたび
Every time I tell a pointless lie,
青い鱗 落ちた
a blue scale slips and falls away.
ガラスの瞳が綺麗で
Those glass eyes are so beautiful.
君のその盲目のように
Just like that blindness of yours,
優しい人になってさ
if I could become a kind person...
そんな僕を愛したいんだよ
I want to love a version of myself like that.
私の呼吸に終わりがあること
Knowing that my breath will one day come to an end,
君の声を覚えている
I still remember the sound of your voice.
生まれては消えてゆくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away—repeating only that over and over again.
僕らがもしまた会えたらなんて思ってた
Thinking to myself, "What if we were able to meet again?"
生まれては消えてゆくだけの 青い波に名前をつけることに
Giving a name to the blue waves that merely come into being and fade away...
意味はなかったのかななんてさ
Wondering if there was ever any meaning to it at all...
たわいない急ぎ足で
With innocent, hurried steps,
積み木で遊んでいる
playing around with building blocks,
崩れるその日を待っている
waiting for the day they fall apart.
澄み切った夜の静寂
In the tranquility of a crystal-clear night,
君の頬の紅色で
dyed in the crimson blush of your cheeks,
もうすぐ桜が咲くだろう
the cherry blossoms will surely bloom soon.
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても
Even if there is no meaning to our breaths,
二人はまた恋をする
the two of us will fall in love once more.
生まれては消えてゆくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away—repeating only that over and over again.
そして君も夜の海に帰っていくんだろう
And you too will eventually return to the night ocean, won't you?
生まれては消えてゆくだけの 青い波に名前をつけることに
Giving a name to the blue waves that merely come into being and fade away...
囚われている
I am trapped by it all...
覚えているかな いつかの春の朝に
Do you still remember? On that spring morning long ago,
桜の木の下で約束したこと
the promise we made beneath the cherry blossom tree...
思い出も君の名前も
Both my memories and your name,
いつの日か失ってしまって
will one day be lost forever,
僕もいつかこの海とひとつになるんだろう
and I too will someday become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気
This winter air without you in it,
僕の頬を刺すその痛みさえ愛していたい
I want to love even the pain that pierces my cheeks.
生まれては消えてゆくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and fading away—repeating only that over and over again.
僕らがもしまた会えたらなんて思ってた
Thinking to myself, "What if we were able to meet again?"
生まれては消えてゆくだけの 青い波に名前をつけることに
Giving a name to the blue waves that merely come into being and fade away...
意味はなかったのかな
Was there really no meaning to it at all...?
こうして冬が終わって
Just like this, winter comes to an end,
青い春が来る
and a blue spring arrives.
UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
Oh child of man who grieves,
UNLUCKY?
人ならざる者も
Even those who are not human,
BE HAPPY!
弛まず目指せよ
Strive without faltering,
生きているんだし
Since you're alive after all.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you turned your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
And the boring future, too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counselling... oh dear, oh dear.
古今東西
All times and places,
一切合切
Everything and all,
ピース ピース
Peace, peace.
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY!
UNDEAD
ねぇねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
何だかどうして
Somehow, why is it,
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
It feels like we're fighting?
触れられない
Can't touch it,
触れたくもない
Don't want to touch it,
過去の自分自分自分自分と
With the past self, self, self, self.
もうとっくに死んでる
Already long dead,
透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep in the innocent, painful memories.
残念？
Regrettable?
もう居ないのに
Even though it's no longer here,
あれ？そっちが良い？
Huh? You prefer that side?
アイロニーね
What irony,
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my current self?
ナンセンス
Nonsense,
消えないレッテル
A label that won't disappear,
要はコンプレックス
In short, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It seems like I'm possessed,
巻き付いたまま
Still wrapped around me,
まだ離れない
Still won't let go,
在りし日の自分
The self of former days.
UNDEAD 死んじゃない
UNDEAD, not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
Living means continuing to change.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness and be satisfied.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly to not even try to be happy.
この世 この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a strange, strange fantasy.
次は何が出るか 鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
What will come next? A demon, or a snake?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting and encountering, the story finally begins.
さあ 人か化物か
Now, human or monster?
閑話休題
Putting all that aside,
ピース ピース
Peace, peace.
Past & Future Can't change the past
Past & Future Run for the future
カットイン
Cut-in.
何だかどうして
Somehow, why is it,
未来になんぞ
In the future,
何の希望もない 期待できないような気がして
Feeling like there's no hope, nothing to expect?
もう随分生きている
Have been living for quite a while,
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Sick of deja vu and cliché templates,
素敵な出来事の気配もない
Not even a sign of wonderful events happening.
残念
Regrettable,
積んだ経験の因果
The karma of accumulated experiences,
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Empty myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I just want stimulation,
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃったなんて
Saying "I got bored, got used to it".
整っていくガイダンス
Guidance falling into order,
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
Seems like it's being capped off,
吸い尽くして
Sucking it dry,
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That, this, and everything all tastes the same.
UNDEAD 死んじゃない
UNDEAD, not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself.
何時の世も 過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In any era, past and future exist in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果せよ
Fulfill the act of living with honest determination.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
UNDEAD 死んじゃない
UNDEAD, not dead,
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness; remain human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just getting used to pain and enduring it,
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
You're as good as dead, a corpse of an undead.
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
UNHAPPY? Oh child of man who grieves,
UNLUCKY? 人ならざる者も
UNLUCKY? Even those who are not human,
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ
BE HAPPY! Strive without faltering,
生きているんだろ
You are alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Drowning in misery or becoming happy,
そう全部全部お前だ
Yes, it's all, all up to you.
古今東西 一切合切
All times and places, everything and all,
森羅万象 ピース ピース
All creation, peace, peace.
Past & Future Can't change the past
Past & Future Run for the future
人の在る所に 眠るということ
Sleeping where humans exist,
生き抜け 化物ばかりの物語
Survive through this story full of monsters!
ちょっとやんちゃで
A little mischievous,
ニコッと元気な
With a bright smile and full of energy,
キラッとスマイル アイドル
A sparkling smile idol!
毎日をもっと楽しくしたいんだ
Wanting to make every single day more fun,
Join us with adventure!
ひらひらスカートも
Even fluttering skirts,
ちゃんと着こなしているんだよ
I wear them stylishly, you know!
だからもっともっと好きになってもいいよ
So it's okay to fall in love with me even more!
一緒に
Together,
大空に飛び立とう
Let's take flight into the open sky!
光るスターライト そんな輝きの中でも強いきらめき
Shining starlight, a strong sparkle even amidst that radiance!
君に届いているかな
Is it reaching you, I wonder?
1ミリでも伝わればいいな
If even a single millimeter conveys, that's enough!
チャージ チャレンジ 全力アクセル
Charge, challenge, full throttle on the gas!
頑張る君へ
To you who works so hard,
一番のりのスマイルを
A fresh, first-rate smile!
駆ける スバル チャンネル
Running Subaru Channel!
エブリデイ 悩んで みんなで
Everyday, worrying together with everyone!
ブルーな気持ちに つばさをかけつけ お助けしちゃうヒーロー
A hero rushing in on wings to help when you feel blue!
弱いハートじゃ いられないから 強い強いで行きましょう
We can't stay with weak hearts, so let's go strong and tough!
ハラハラな水着で どきどきの抱きしめタイム
In thrilling swimsuits, it's a heart-pounding hug time!
降り立つよ パラダイスと感動
Descending into paradise and emotion!
曇り空 吹き飛ばそう
Let's blow away the cloudy skies!
あがれさまい こんな暗闇の中でも 眩しく照らす
Rising up high, shining brightly even in darkness like this!
君に見つけてもらえた それだけでも
Just the fact that you found me...
運命なんだ 続く道は続いてく 夢に向かって
...is fate itself! The road keeps going on toward our dreams!
一緒に生きてくれるかな その手をとって走れ 連れて行くよ みんなで
Will you walk through life with me? Take my hand and run, I'll take everyone along!
囁く 恥ずかしいけれど
Whispering, even though I feel embarrassed...
伝えたい思い 今なら言える
...the feelings I want to convey, I can say them now.
君のエールが力になるよ いつも元気を分けてくれて
Your cheers become my strength, always sharing your energy with me.
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
I can keep giving my best and spending days smiling, truly!
ありがとうの気持ちを 歌えたら
If I can sing out my feelings of gratitude...
こんな輝きの中でも 強くきらめき
Even amidst such brilliance, shining strongly!
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if just a tiny bit gets across, that's enough.
続く道は続いてく 夢に向かって
The road keeps continuing toward our dreams!
一緒に生きてくれるかな その手をとって走れ 連れて行くよ みんなで
Will you walk through life with me? Take my hand and run, I'll take everyone along!
君と駆ける スバル
Running together with you, Subaru!
スバル先輩ありがとうございました！家宝にします！
Subaru-senpai, thank you so much! I'll treasure this forever!
こぼ頑張れー！
Go for it, Kobo!
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
誰かのための痛み
Pain endured for someone else,
僕の願い やがて散りぢり
my wishes scatter before long.
リストリー GAMEみたい
Re-story, like a game,
それでも息をしていくしかない
even so, I have no choice but to keep breathing.
まだ聞こえるか 遠くのほうで瞬く呼吸
Can you still hear it? Breathing flickering in the distance.
関係ないノイズは 雑音だけ聞こえてる
Irrelevant noise, heard only as a nuisance.
あんたなんてさ もうすべてを振り切る
Someone like you, I'll shake everything off now...
SPEEDで
...with SPEED.
この瞬間まであがいて ただのしがみついて
Struggling right up to this moment, just holding on...
今見ゆるとこまで
...to wherever I can see right now.
この瞬間を飲み干して また踊って
Gulping down this moment, dancing again...
見たことないもの見せて
...show me something I've never seen before.
君の代わりはいない
There is no replacement for you.
もし誰かが否定しても
Even if someone denies it,
僕の代わりはいない
there is no replacement for me.
疑うことない僕の証明
The undeniable proof of who I am.
誰かの祈りでは払えない痛み
Pain that someone's prayers cannot dispel,
どこからか漂う悪意の兆し
signs of malice wafting from somewhere.
正しさに息を潜めたいなら
If you want to hold your breath in righteousness,
それすら僕の答えであり
even that is my answer.
誰かの情熱を奪う感覚
The sensation of stealing someone's passion,
逃げる気はどうにもないのさ
I have no intention of running away.
喉で呼吸するほどさ 錯覚を起こしたのさ
Breathing through my throat so hard, it caused an illusion.
まだ見えてるか 遠くにスポットライトがあたる
Can you still see it? The spotlight shining in the distance.
関係ないノイズは 自分だけに聞かせてる
Irrelevant noise, letting only myself hear it.
あんたなんてさ もうすべてを振り切る
Someone like you, I'll shake everything off now...
SPEEDで
...with SPEED.
この瞬間だけあがいたって意味ないぜ 今見ゆるとこまで
Struggling only for this moment is meaningless, to wherever I can see right now.
大乱感で生き合って また踊って 見たことないもの見せて
Surviving in wild sensation, dancing again, show me something never seen before.
今を撃ち抜いて もうノーストップで 脳擦り切れるまで
Piercing through the present, nonstop now, until my brain wears out.
この瞬間を飲み干して また踊って
Gulping down this moment, dancing again...
見たことないもの見せて
...show me something I've never seen before.
さあ この瞬間を目に焼き付けて
Now, burn this moment into your eyes,
また踊って 見たことないもの見せて
dance again, and show me something I've never seen before.
連れていかれるように
As if being led away,
踏み出した暗い街へ
I stepped out into the dark town.
Tell me what you need 後追う背中は
Tell me what you need; the back I was chasing
黒く染まってた
was dyed in black.
Wait hold up 悪党？それとも正義？ Huh?
Wait, hold up. A villain? Or justice? Huh?
やりがい Searching 馬鹿みたい
Searching for worth, feeling like a fool.
目の前の問題は It's too much now
The problem before me, it's too much now.
後回しでもまあ良いじゃん
Putting it off is fine too, right?
人生の意味 結局何？
What is the meaning of life in the end?
不安定な日々に裏返る声
Voices cracking in these unstable days.
あれこれ言っている間に 姿を消し去った君は誰？
While talking about this and that, who are you that disappeared?
曖昧な世界が変わったあの日
That day when the ambiguous world changed,
ど派手に描き鳴らした声が まだ今も鳴り止まない
the voice that resounded so flashily still hasn't stopped echoing now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に 君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
増えてく影を追い
Chasing the multiplying shadows,
気づけば遠い街で
before I knew it, I was in a distant town.
引き返し元通りになるのには もう遅かった
It was already too late to turn back and return to normal.
Wait hold up now SOS 逃げ場がないの えっちょっと待って
Wait, hold up now, SOS, there's no escape! Wait a minute,
How is it my fault?
レフト、ライト ステップからの
From left, right steps,
Get downに見せかけて Clap
pretending to get down, then clap.
からかっていて立場は対等？
Teasing around, is our standing equal?
助けてやって何その態度
I helped you, so what's with that attitude?
不満の中で生まれた依存症
An addiction born from dissatisfaction,
垣間見えるのは愛
what's glimpsed is love.
退屈な世界が変わったあの日
That day when the boring world changed,
ど派手に描き鳴らした声が まだ今も鳴り止まない
the voice that resounded so flashily still hasn't stopped echoing now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に 君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
はい、はい 腹から声出していこう
Yes, yes, let's project from our stomach!
そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
Keep that up and you're gonna get hurt!
勝敗かけた歌合戦
A song battle with victory on the line,
枯れそうな地声で まだ歌うのさ
with a voice about to wither, I'm still singing!
ど派手に描き鳴らした声が まだ今も鳴り止まない
The voice that resounded so flashily still hasn't stopped echoing now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に 君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
はい、はい 腹から声出して そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
Yes, yes, project from your stomach! Keep that up and you'll get hurt!
紅の夜に心奪われて
My heart captivated by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に 君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
All eyes on me...
All eyes on me
駆け引き探って
Probing for tactics,
あーごめんねって
saying "Ah, I'm sorry,"
意味がないね
it's completely meaningless.
タグ付けある孤立感
A feeling of isolation with tagged labels,
見て取りたい
I want to perceive it.
じゃあどうなりたい？
Then, what do you want to become?
そっと暴いて
Gently expose it:
二重で被る面相
the double-layered disguise worn.
優しい言葉並べて
Arranging gentle words,
2人お揃いに甘えて
indulging in being a matching pair,
演じてみせているのは誰のため？
who is this performance being put on for?
ただ泣いたように笑っていたんだ
I was just smiling as if I had cried.
All eyes on me 偽りの This fake
All eyes on me, this fake of falsehoods,
愛なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand what love even is.
All eyes on me いつの間にか This fake
All eyes on me, before I knew it, this fake.
All eyes on me... This fake
重ね重ねお詫びします
I apologize repeatedly,
気持ちのない口癖
a habitual phrase devoid of emotion.
優しさにズルさも履き違えて
Mistaking selfishness for kindness,
重ね重ね
over and over...
戯言の吐息だけで
With just the breath of nonsense,
満たされるマスク
a mask that gets fulfilled,
まだ二重で縛ってる
still bound in double layers.
心の中 散々と取り繕っている
Terrible excuses patch up what's inside my heart.
ほんとの顔は誰のためで
Who is my true face for?
だんだん苦しくなるね
It's getting harder and harder to breathe, isn't it?
お揃いの名前の前で
In front of matching names,
ただ泣いてないで笑っていたいよ
I just want to smile without crying.
Oh, eyes on me いつまでも Free forever
Oh, eyes on me, free forever, always.
愛なんて分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't even understand what love is.
Oh, eyes on me いっそ非に果てて Fake out
Oh, eyes on me, I'd rather burn away and fake out.
脱いでみたい 演技でもないなら
I want to strip it off, if it's not an act...
それまで勝った 寄せ集めから
from the miscellany gathered up until now,
胸に秘めている Deep fake out
hiding deep inside my chest, Deep fake out.
泣かないように笑っていたんだ
I was smiling so I wouldn't cry.
Oh, eyes on me 偽りの Deep fake out
Oh, eyes on me, a fake Deep fake out.
愛なんて分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't even understand what love is.
Oh, eyes on me いつの間にか Deep fake out
Oh, eyes on me, before I knew it, Deep fake out.
Oh, eyes, eyes on me, fake out
みんな、どうでしたか？
How was it, everyone?
いやぁ、今回はですね、ハウスにね、初めて挑戦したんですけれども...
Wow, this time I challenged myself to House dance for the first time...
あの、2ヶ月で、あの、詰め込んで踊れてましたか？
Um, did I manage to cram it into 2 months and dance well?
「めっちゃ頑張った」ってコメントが書いてくれてるんだろうなぁ！
I'm sure the comments are saying "You worked so hard!", right?
いやぁいやぁ。でね、『波に名前をつけること』『僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること』って曲では
Yeah, yeah. And, you know, in the songs "Nami ni Namae wo Tsukeru Koto" and "Bokura no Kokyuu ni Owari ga Aru Koto",
リフトをしたり、くるくる回ったり、あれも初めてやりました！ 踊れてたら嬉しいな！
doing lifts and spinning around—I did that for the first time too! I hope I danced it well!
ゲストの白雪先輩、ハジ先輩ともキレキレに踊って...
I danced sharply with guest Shirayuki-senpai and Haji-senpai...
スバル先輩とは、憧れのスバル先輩と2人きりでドキドキタイムもしちゃったり...
With Subaru-senpai, my admired Subaru-senpai, we had a nervous duo time...
ロボ子さんといろは先輩、なでちゃんとは対決しまくって！ ルイせんとマリンちゃんは勝手、エフジーとはかっこよく...
With Roboko-san, Iroha-senpai, and Nade-chan, we had showdowns! With Lui-sen and Marine-chan, and EFZY, super cool...
ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか！
There were so many wonderful guest parts, weren't there?
ということで、皆さん！何か忘れてませんかね？
So, everyone! Haven't you forgotten something?
ね、皆さん。ちょっと水みずの休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない。
Hey, everyone. My little water break time has to end soon too.
よっし、立つか！
Alright, time to stand up!
はい！ということで、なんとですね、こんな感じで言うのも何なんですが...
Okay! So, believe it or not, it's a bit strange to say it like this, but...
新曲が出まーす！イェーイ！
A new song is coming out! Yay!
初のオリジナル楽曲！
My very first original song!
やばい、体が疲れた。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Oh no, my body is tired. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
はい、ということで、作詞・作曲・編曲はサトダユーリさんに作ってもらいました！
Okay, so the lyrics, composition, and arrangement were made by Satoda Yuuri-san!
ありがと！ドンドンパフパフ！ドンドンパフパフ！
Thank you! *cheering noises*
この後すぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わった後あるのですが！
Right after this, the MV release will happen right after this stream ends!
リダイレクトで飛びます！そしてデジタルリリースは今日の0時ろくからなので、たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
It will redirect automatically! And the digital release is from midnight today, so I'd be happy if you listen to it a lot!
じゃ、ちょっと早速なんですが、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな？
Well, right away, shall I reveal that new song?
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろう？気になるな！どんな楽曲なんだろう？いきます！
Man, I wonder what kind of song it is? I'm so curious! What kind of song is it? Here we go!
うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ うみゃうにゃ
Umyu unya, umyu unya...
くるるん くるるん あ～そろそろごはんの時間かな？
*stomach growl* Ah~ Is it almost time for food?
あ、でもでも、やっぱやっぱ 家から一歩も出たくない～
Ah, but still, I really really don't wanna step a foot outside home~
こんな時はそうだ 飯テロの動画！
At times like this, right! Food porn videos!
（説明しよう！極限までお腹を空かし 美味しくいただくのだ！）
(Let me explain! Starve yourself to the extreme so it tastes delicious!)
めんどい めんどい マジめんどいわ
So troublesome, so annoying, seriously troublesome!
結局ぐだぐだ時間溶けたわ
In the end, time just melted away slacking off!
ぴろりん ぴろりん 5回目アラーム
*ring ring* 5th time alarm!
コンビニいこー
Let's go to the convenience store~
わちゃわちゃ はちゃめちゃ 奇想天外
Chaotic, frantic, fantastical!
ドタバタ 展展開 見逃せない
A wild sequence of events you can't miss!
ピンチだってちょちょいのちょいで
Even a pinch is super easy-peasy!
てやっ！てやっ！そりゃっ！そりゃっ！
Hah! Hah! Take that! Take that!
万事解決☆
Everything is resolved!☆
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ おいしくなーれ
Umyu, umyu, umyu, umyu, become delicious!
あれもこれも全部食べたいの
I want to eat all of that and this!
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ ハピネスらいふ
Munch munch, umyu umyu, happiness life!
食べて寝て遊んで また食べる！
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ぺこぺこ ぺこぺこ はらぺこじゃ
*rumble rumble* So hungry!
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うまくいきませーん
Umyu umyu umyu, it's not going well~
ひとまずごはんをお腹いーっぱい
First of all, fill your belly with food!
食べさせてよ！
Let me eat!
うみゃ うみゃ
Umyu umyu!
うにゃ うにゃ
Unya unya!
うみゃ うみゃ
Umyu umyu!
あ〜いい天気〜 あの雲ソフトクリームみたい！
Ah, such nice weather~ That cloud looks like soft-serve ice cream!
あ、あっちはわたがし！
Ah, that one is cotton candy!
雲ってふわふわでおいしそう…
Clouds look so fluffy and delicious...
人生で1回は食べてみたいよね〜
I'd like to try eating one at least once in my life~
じゃない！
Not!
しんどいしんどいまじしんどいわ
So tough, so tough, seriously so tough.
現実逃避何度もしちゃうわ
I keep escaping reality over and over.
妄想 空想 頭が暴走
Delusions, daydreams, my head is running wild.
カツオ食べたーい！！！
I wanna eat bonito-!
だらだらぐたら 怠惰全開
Lazing around, full-on laziness.
ネガティブ思考をご愛敬です！
Negative thoughts are just part of my charm!
世界だってぽいぽいのぽいで
Even the world, I'll just toss it away.
えいやっ えいやっ どりゃっ どりゃっ
Eiya, eiya, dorya, dorya!
ねじ伏せちゃうぞ☆
I'll pin it down!☆
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ お腹すいたら
Umya umya umya umya, when I get hungry...
突撃！隣の晩ごはん
Raid! Next door's dinner.
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ しあわせタイム
Munch munch, umya umya, happy time!
主に食欲で生きてます
I live mostly on appetite.
だからどうかお願い
So please, I beg of you...
このおなかを満たして神様
Fill this belly of mine, God!
食べたい！ 寝てたい！
Wanna eat! Wanna sleep!
むずかしいことは何も考えたくない
I don't wanna think about anything difficult.
「おとと、みんなでお菓子パーティをしたーい！」
"Ototo, I wanna have a snack party with everyone-!"
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ おいしくなーれ
Umya umya umya umya, become delicious~
あれもこれも全部食べたいな
I wanna eat all of this and that.
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ ハピネスライフ
Munch munch, umya umya, happiness life!
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べる！
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ぺこぺこぺこぺこ はらぺこちゃん
Rumbling, rumbling, hungry little girl.
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ 食いしん坊
Umya umya umya umya, glutton!
ひとまずごはんをお腹いっぱい
For now, fill my belly with food!
食べさせて！
Feed me!
まだ足りない
Still not enough!
もっともっと 食べさせて！
Feed me more and more!
新曲どうだったー？
How was the new song?
可愛かったでしょ〜？
It was super cute, right~?
「可愛い」っていうコメントがたくさん見えます！
I see so many comments saying "cute"!
ありがとうね！「可愛い」「可愛い」ありがとう！知ってる知ってる！
Thank you! "Cute", "cute", thank you! I know, I know!
ということでね！新曲のタイトルは『うみゃうにゃはっぴーらいふ』でしたー！
So, the title of the new song was "Umya Unya Happy Life"!
今回はちょっと可愛い感じにしたので、次はなんかカッコいい感じにしたいな〜みたいな、まあ何も決まってないんですけどね！
I made it cute this time, so maybe next time I'll make it cool~ Well, nothing's decided yet!
ということで！新曲が終わったからって、帰ろうとしてない？
So! Just because the new song is over, you're not trying to leave, are you?
ねぇ？なんか忘れてるよね、みんな？
Hey? Everyone's forgetting something, right?
と、いうことで！
And so!
グッズー！
Merch-!
水宮枢 誕生日記念2026のグッズを早速一つずつ見ていこうー！
Let me show you the Mizumiya Su Birthday Celebration 2026 merch one by one!
まずは、こちらー！
First up, this one-!
オーロラアクリルパネル！
Aurora Acrylic Panel!
公式イラストレーターの、ぶくろてママに描いてもらいました！ありがとう、ママ〜！
It was drawn by official illustrator Bukurote-mama! Thank you, Mama-!
ふわふわのね、お部屋で、お茶会みたいなね、可愛い感じになっております！
It has a cute feel, like a tea party in a fluffy room!
もうママが天才すぎるので、ぜひ買ってください！
Mama is just too much of a genius, so please buy it!
2つ目は、こちらー！
The second item is this one-!
ハート型缶バッジ！ハート、ハート、ハート！
Heart-shaped Tin Badge! Heart, heart, heart!
こちらはね、もう可愛いお顔がドアップになって、で、すーたぶんハート型の缶バッジは初めてなんじゃないかなと思っているので、
This features a close-up of my cute face, and I think it's my first heart-shaped badge,
ぜひこちらも買ってみてください！
so please try getting this one too!
3つ目が、こちら！
The third one is this!
おくるみすーぬいぐるみ！
Swaddled Su Plushie!
こちらもね、すーちゃんがおくるみに入っています！まあ、なんかすーをね、結構おくるみに入れてくれてる方も見たりとかしたので、
Su-chan is inside a swaddle! I've seen some of you put Su in swaddles before,
もしかしたらみんな、こういうのを待っていたんじゃないかなと思って、作りました！
so I thought maybe you were waiting for something like this and made it!
衣装はね、キービジュアルの衣装で、ちょっと小さめのぬいぐるみを作ってみましたー！
The outfit is from the key visual, and I made a slightly smaller plushie-!
4つ目は、こちら！
The fourth item is this!
れきおー推し活ショルダーバッグ！
Rekio Oshi-katsu Shoulder Bag!
こちらにですね、さっきのハート型のね、缶バッジとか、おくるみ plushie/ぬいぐるみが入れられるようになっています！
You can put the heart badge or swaddled plushie inside this bag!
はい、天才！天才！天才！ということで、こちらも一緒にぜひれきおーのね、推し活のバッグに入れて、
Yes, genius! Genius! Genius! So put them in your Rekio fan-activity bag,
すーをね、あの、可愛く持っていってください！よろしくねー！
and carry Su around cute-style! Please do~!
他の推しもぜひ入れてみてねー！
Feel free to put your other oshis in it too!
5つ目が、こちら！
The fifth item is this!
ボイス！タイトルは、「すーとお茶会」！
Voice pack! The title is "Tea Party with Su"!
こちらはね、おうちで優雅な優雅な優雅なアフタヌーンティーを楽しむすーと一緒にね、
In this one, you can enjoy an elegant afternoon tea at home together with Su,
いっぱい楽しんじゃうボイスとなっております！
it's a voice pack full of fun!
最後に、フルセット！
Lastly, the Full Set!
直筆サイン入りオリジナルカードと、ASMRボイスがついてきまーす！
It comes with a hand-signed original card and ASMR voice pack!
おうちに お呼ばれされちゃったみんながね
All of you who got invited over to my house,
ちょっと距離近めでね
from a pretty close distance,
ASMRボイスが
the ASMR voice...
ちょっとこんな感じで... ま、ちょっと適当なんですけど
is kind of like this... well, I'm kind of winging it,
ま、そんな感じのボイスになっております！
but that's what the voice track is like!
こちら
This one...
数量限定で...
is limited quantity...
ない！
NOT!
ので、焦らずに
So don't rush,
みんなゆっくりで大丈夫です！
everyone can take your time!
グッズは22時...
The merch sales start at 22...
ん？
Huh?
22時10分から販売開始です！
Sales start at 22:10!
直筆のサインとかもね、もう全部
Hand-signed items too, all of them,
もう何もかも数量限定じゃないので
absolutely everything is NOT limited quantity,
あの、すぅちゃんのサインも
so Su-chan's signature
あの、ついてきますのでね、フルセットを買ったら
will be included if you buy the full set,
皆さんよろしくお願いします！ぜひ！
so please consider it, everyone! Definitely!
買ってねー！
Please buy it!
いっぱい買ってー！
Buy lots of them!
はい！
Alright!
と、いうことで
And with that,
以上、ミニみやによるグッズ紹介でした！
that was the merch showcase by Mini-Miya!
はい！ということで、ミニみやありがとー！
Alright! So, thank you Mini-Miya!
なんか結構ミスってたな...
She made quite a few mistakes...
まあミニみやだからね、すぅじゃないから
Well, she's Mini-Miya, not Su-chan,
ま、しゃーないか！
so I guess it can't be helped!
ということで、誕生日の...
So, how was...
3Dライブはどうだったでしょうかー？
...the birthday 3D live stream?
憧れのホロライブに入ってから
Ever since I joined Hololive, which I dreamed of,
みんながいっぱい応援してもらって、ここまで来れました！
everyone gave me so much support, and I've come this far!
みんなに少しでもね、「かっこよかった」とか
If you felt even a little bit like "that was cool,"
「すぅちゃんのこと応援しててよかった」って
or "I'm glad I supported Su-chan,"
思ってもらえてたら、とっても嬉しいです！
I would be so very happy!
MVはこのあとすぐ公開で
The MV will be premiered right after this,
リダイレクトで飛ぶので
and it will redirect automatically,
チャンネルはそのままで、よろしくお願いします！
so please stay tuned on this channel!
ということで、みんな
With that said, everyone,
これからもよろしくねー！
please keep supporting me!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
じゃあ
Well then,
ばいばーい！またねー！
Bye-bye! See you!
すずりすへ
[On-screen message: To Suzuris,]
すぅを見つけて 応援してくれてありがとう！
Thank you for finding Su and supporting me!
そのおかげで こんなにすてきな景色が見られたし
Thanks to you, I was able to see such a wonderful sight,
じまんの推しになれたよ！
and become an oshi you can be proud of!
これからもガンガン押していくので ついてきてね！
I'll keep pushing forward full speed ahead, so please follow me!
すぅががんばれるのは すずりすのおかげ！！
The reason Su can do her best is all thanks to Suzuris!!